DIMITRA GIANTSIDI

https://dgiantsidi.github.io/ · dimitra.giantsidi@gmail.com Informatics Forum 1.05, University of Edinburgh 10 Crichton Street, EH8 9AB, Edinburgh, United Kingdom

RESEARCH INTERESTS

I like to build robust and efficient distributed systems!

I am a final year PhD student at the University of Edinburgh, UK and as part of my research, I have worked on some interesting projects: a secure distributed transactional store (Trusted Execution Environments, RDMA and RocksDB), a shielded direct I/O network library for secure replication (Crash Fault Tolerance and BFT) and a fast shared log for serverless computing infrastuctures (byte addressable storage, gRPC/TCP). I am currently designing a trusted NIC architecture for large-scale distributed systems based on SmartNICs.

EDUCATION

PhD in Computer Science

Sept 2019 - present

University of Edinburgh, UK

- · Sponsors: Microsoft Research, UK Rise, Advisor: Prof. Dr. Pramod Bhatotia
- · Distributed systems, systems security, replication protocols

MSc in Computer Science

Sept 2018 - Aug 2019

University of Edinburgh, UK

· Best Performing Female MSc Thesis Award

MEng in Computer and Electrical Engineering

Sept 2012 - Feb 2018

National Technical University of Athens (NTUA), Greece

EMPLOYMENT

Microsoft Research, Cambridge, UK

Sept 2021 - Dec 2021

Research Scientist Intern

 \cdot Design of KVs for timing attacks.

University of Edinburgh, UK

June 2023 - present

 $Research\ Assistant$

· Hardware/software co-design of a trusted NIC architecture.

Intracom Telecom, Athens, Greece

Jul 2017 - Jul 2018

 $Software \ \& \ Systems \ Engineer$

· Performance and energy optimization of NFV services.

Unversity of Edinburgh, UK and TUM, Germany

Sept 2019 - present

Thesis advisor and Teaching Assistant

- · Operating Systems, Distributed Computing, Parallel Architectures, Object-oriented Programming.
- · Supervised five BSc/MSc students on their BSc Thesis on Distributed and Networking systems.

PUBLICATIONS

Anchor: Secure Persistent Memory Architecture.

Dimitris Stravakakis, Dimitra Giantsidi, Maurice Bailleu, Philip Saendig, Shady Issa, Pramod Bhatotia.

SIGMOD'24

Flex Log: A Shared Log for Stateful Serverless Computing.

Dimitra Giantsidi, Emmanouil Giortamis, Nathaniel Tornow, Florin Dinu, Pramod Bhatotia.

ACM HPDC'23

Treaty: Secure Distributed Transactions.

Dimitra Giantsidi, Maurice Bailleu, Natacha Crooks, Pramod Bhatotia.

IEEE/IFIP DSN'22 (Best paper nominee)

Avocado: A Secure In-Memory Distributed Storage System.

Maurice Bailleu, Dimitra Giantsidi, Vasilis Gavrielatos, Le Quoc Do, Vijay Nagarajan, Pramod Bhatotia.

USENIX ATC'21

DICER: Diligent Cache Partitioning for Efficient Workload Consolidation.

 $Konstantinos\ Nikas,\ Nikela\ Papadopoulou,\ Dimitra\ Giantsidi,\ Vasileios\ Karakostas,\ Georgios\ Goumas,\ Nectarios\ Koziris.$

ICPP'19

TALKS

ACM HPDC'23, Orlando, US

FlexLog: A Shared Log for Stateful Serverless Computing.

IEEE/IFIP DSN'22, Baltimore, US

Treaty: Secure Distributed Transactions.

Third Annual SGX Community Day 2022 (virtual)

USENIX ATC'21 (virtual) Avocado: A Secure In-Memory Distributed Storage System.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages C/C++, Python, Bash, Golang, Java, Vitis HLS

Systems Programming RocksDB and folly libraries, TEEs (Intel SGX, OpenEnclave SDK, AMD-sev),

direct network I/O (DPDK, RDMA, Alveo SmartNICs), SPDK,

Intel RDT, LLVM, collectd, POSIX/Unix, OpenMP and MPI, gRPC

Virtualization KVM, Qemu/Libvirt, Docker, Kubernetes

Version Control Git

Distributed Programming Hadoop MapReduce, Socket and RPC programming

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

EuroSys'21

 $Web\ chair.$

EuroSys'23, SoCC'23, WWW'22

 $Shadow\ PC\ member.$

HONORS AND AWARDS

Microsoft Research Award	2019
Best Performing Female MSc Student Award, University of Edinburgh	2019
Highest Honors award	2012